cox.com 2019-07-20

# Annual Privacy Notice | Cox Communications

## Your Privacy Rights as a Cox Customer and Related Information

### **Notice to Cox Residential Customers**

**In keeping with our commitment to be the most trusted provider of communications and entertainment services, we are letting you know how we will collect and use your Personally Identifiable Information. We work to keep it secure and will destroy it when no longer needed by us for any reason. We will give you clear, prior notice and the right to choose, as described below, how your Personally Identifiable Information will be used.**

We cannot cover here every situation that affects your information, but we have included those we believe are of most interest to you. We also offer updates for you at  _[Cox.com](http://www.cox.com/)_. Any updates are effective as of the date first published on Cox.com. If you receive your bills electronically, we will send this notice by email. If you would like a written copy, contact us at  _[privacy@cox.com](mailto:privacy@cox.com)_.

### What Do We Collect?

**Your Information**

In providing our services, we sometimes collect personally identifiable information, such as your name, physical address, telephone numbers, social security number, driver's license number, and email addresses ("Personally Identifiable Information"). We may also collect other non-personally identifiable information, such as information about premium services, general location, demographics, billing information, maintenance, repair, services, equipment, software, usage, settings and preferences to aid in customer support and in recommendations for you. If non-personally identifiable information is directly linked to Personally Identifiable Information, it will be considered Personally Identifiable Information while it is linked. Aggregate and/or de-identified information is not considered Personally Identifiable Information.

Our policy is to collect Personally Identifiable Information to help us provide the services we may offer with the quality you deserve. We take reasonable precautions to identify you or persons you have authorized when we are contacted about your Cox account. We sometimes ask for Personally Identifiable Information for special reasons, such as for research, in surveys or registering for our apps or at our websites. If so, we will tell you first how we will use it, and you may choose not to participate.

**Cable Television Services**  
We may use various technologies, including the cable set-top box, our websites and mobile apps, to collect information about your video selections. We treat this information as confidential, and we will not use it to identify you, without your consent, to third parties other than affiliates, vendors and business partners furthering our business activities related to your services. We use this information to make recommendations to you and for other service-related purposes, such as to market new or additional services to you.  We provide an option for you to opt-out of our use of your viewing information for video recommendations for most devices by using the settings menu on your set-top box or application.

We collect and use viewing information, as described above, and demographic and other information and may share the information, when de-identified, with others for programming, ratings, marketing, advertising and similar purposes. Also, limited Personally Identifiable Information is collected and used in providing some types of cable television services, such as pay-per view, interactive, entertainment-on-demand and devices we provide to you.

**Internet Services**  
Like most Internet service providers, we automatically collect and store Internet Protocol (IP) addresses (an identifier given to your connection while online), the volume of data transmitted and received through your service, Internet connection performance, modem MAC addresses, and connection dates and times. We may also collect and store other usage statistics, such as the volume of data transmitted by protocols, devices and services, to help us understand how our network is used and to tailor the services we offer. If you are accessing the Internet away from your home through a WiFi connection provided by Cox or its partners, we may also collect the device MAC ID, device type, location of the access point, duration and session information.

**Applications**

We offer "apps" to customers to access certain services. Unless another privacy policy is associated with the app, this privacy notice governs your use of such apps. The app terms and conditions accompanying the apps may also detail special terms concerning their collection and use of information.

**Telephone Services**  
In providing telephone services, we collect usage information, including calls made and received and their duration. We treat this information as private and retain it in most jurisdictions for up to eighteen months. We do not share these records with others, unless required by law. Except when required by law, we do not listen to or record your calls to third parties. We do monitor and record calls with Cox customer care agents for quality and training purposes.

**Cox Homelife**  
Home security and automation services offered by Cox are subject to this privacy notice and the terms, conditions and privacy provisions contained in the applicable home security service agreement.

### What Information Do We Use or Share?

**Personally Identifiable Information**  
We consider Personally Identifiable Information confidential, and use it only as provided in this privacy notice.  Personally Identifiable Information is used, for example, for the following activities: sales, installation, training, operations, administration, advertising, marketing, support, development of new products and services, data analytics, network management, maintenance, customer care, communications with you, billing and collection. We may combine Personally Identifiable Information with demographic and other information for purposes consistent with this notice.

**Sharing Restrictions**  
It is our policy not to disclose Personally Identifiable Information to persons outside of Cox, other than our affiliates, vendors and business partners, without your prior consent or as otherwise specified in this statement. The sharing of Personally Identifiable Information with our affiliates, vendors and business partners is in connection with the provision of Cox services. In addition, the Cable Act allows us to disclose limited Personally Identifiable Information to third-parties for mailing list or other purposes, subject to your ability to limit this disclosure. You can opt-out of this type of disclosure by changing your preferences on <https://www.cox.com/privacyrequest>. Any mailing list or other disclosure will not reveal, directly or indirectly, your viewing or other use of our cable or other services or the nature of any transaction made over our cable system.

**Aggregate and De-Identified Information**  
We use and share aggregate or de-identified information about usage by groups of customers for a variety of purposes. Aggregate and de-identified information does not identify individual customers. We use aggregate or de-identified information along with data from other sources and may share it with others.

**Outside Parties and Vendors**  
We sometimes use affiliates, vendors or partners in providing services to you and may share Personally Identifiable Information for these purposes. We require these parties to maintain at least the same level of confidentiality we maintain ourselves. We also prohibit them from using Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than providing the services on our behalf.

**Telephone Services**  
Customer Care can help you with your PIN including how to find it and change it. At Cox retail locations, telephone customers must show a government-issued photo ID before we can discuss your information. If you, or anyone authorized by you, make certain changes to your telephone account, Cox will send you notice to confirm that you made these changes. If you suspect that someone may have made unauthorized changes to your account, contact Customer Care at the telephone number on your bill. If we discover any unauthorized access to your telephone account, we will send you notice, in keeping with applicable law.

Our telephone customers can designate their listings as non-published for print or electronic directories or for directory assistance services. We do not publish these directories and are not responsible for their content or accuracy. Because of the complexity of this process and the involvement of others, errors sometimes occur. Our telephone services are subject to tariff or contractual terms that limit our liability in the event of listing errors. For more information on telephone privacy, see the _Customer Proprietary Network Information_ notice below.

**Cable Television Services**  
When you use an interactive service to participate in or to order a product or service, you are sharing your contact information with the appropriate party. As explained above, we also use viewing information for certain purposes.

**Internet Services**  
Unless addressed to us, we do not read the content of your online communications, unless required by law or court order. We may, however, retain and provide such communications if we are legally required to do so. For the email accounts that are provided by us, we generally scan incoming and outgoing email traffic electronically to identify and filter out likely spam. We may use email to send transactional, informational, or relationship messages related to your service. However, we will never ask you to send personal information to us by unsecured email. If you prefer, you may opt-out of marketing messages we send by notifying us in response to the email you receive, through the unsubscribe link found at the bottom of the email. We monitor our network for malware and other threats that could harm your equipment, the network or other users. We may communicate with you online concerning such threats, as well as offerings from Cox that you may be interested in. For more information, see our  _[Policies at Cox.com](http://www.cox.com/aboutus/policies.cox)_. We also provide general location-based online advertising based on your general geographic area and nine-digit ZIP code, similar to direct mail you receive through the U.S. Mail. Visit [Location-Based Advertising](https://www.cox.com/residential/support/opting-out-of-location-based-advertising.html) for more information and instructions on opting out of this service.

**Special Exceptions**

We reserve the right to disclose Personally Identifiable Information if we have a good faith belief it is necessary to: (1) comply with the law; (2) protect our network, rights or property or those of others; (3) respond to fraud, abuse or unauthorized reception; (4) enforce our  _[Policies posted on Cox.com;](http://www.cox.com/aboutus/policies.cox)_  or (5) act in an emergency to protect your safety or that of another person. We may also transfer Personally Identifiable Information as a part of a sale or transfer of our business operations.

### What Should I Know About Internet Security?

**Taking Proper Precautions**  
Maintaining the security of your personal computer is an important way to protect your privacy and to help us protect our network and customers. You must follow our policies posted on Cox.com and maintain your antivirus software, firewall, wireless network security and your operating system to prevent harm and potential theft of data. You should regularly back up your computer to preserve your files, including messages you want to keep, and change your login password regularly. Always be sure you know with whom you are dealing before clicking on an Internet link or giving personal information. When communications enter the Internet, it is possible for outside parties to access them. Since we cannot control websites or services operated by third parties, you should review their terms of service and privacy policies before use. We encourage you to visit our website at Cox.com or the Federal Trade Commission ("FTC") at [https://www.ftc.gov](https://www.ftc.gov/) for tips on protecting yourself and your personal information.

We may take protective action related to your Internet service or contact you to help with security issues we identify, such as malware infections. Unsecured WiFi home networks can make you vulnerable to a number of problems, such as unauthorized persons using your Internet service. We may check for unsecured Wi-Fi networks attached to Cox Internet service and provide instructions to you on how to secure them. We monitor our network and scan incoming and outgoing cox.com email messages to filter out likely spam, harmful messages, viruses, malware, spyware and related threats that could harm your equipment, the network or others. We may also share network traffic data, including IP addresses, with trusted third parties who work to protect ISPs and the Internet from botnets and other threats.

**Spam**  
We try to block incoming and outgoing spam using a variety of methods. You can help by preventing unauthorized access to your computer. You can forward unwanted spam to _[spamreport@cox.net](mailto:spamreport@cox.net)_  and phishing scams to  _[phishingreport@cox.net](mailto:phishingreport@cox.net)_  to help update our filters. We will never ask you to send personal information to us by unsecured email.

### Cookies and Online Advertisements

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
We and other parties may place ads on our websites and emails using "cookies" and web beacons or clear GIFs or other similar technologies to collect information about your visit to our website, your viewing of our ads and emails, and to manage your preferences. These tools do not provide any information that personally identifies you. They can, however, be read by the provider to note information about your visit, such as your type of browser, operating system and IP address. Cookies may also help to recognize you when you log in as a registered user or as a repeat visitor. You can control the cookies your computer accepts through the settings on your device. Doing so, however, may limit the personalization available to you. We use these tools to tailor our site and email to better serve you by remembering you and any options you select. We may share non-personal information obtained from these tools with vendors, advertisers and others.

**Online Advertising**  
When you use our services, Cox may display advertisements, public service announcements, and other messages to you. Location-based online advertising is based upon your nine-digit ZIP code, similar to direct mail you receive through U.S. mail. Visit [Location-Based Advertising](https://www.cox.com/residential/support/opting-out-of-location-based-advertising.html) for more information and instructions on opting out of this service.

**Behavioral or Interest-Based Ad Options**  
Cox and other website owners or advertisers may use cookies or other tools to provide customized ads based on visits to third-party websites. You can find more information about these tools, including benefits they can provide at [https://www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/). Many companies that collect information for behavioral advertising are members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"). NAI offers the ability for you to opt-out of the behavioral advertising programs of their members by going to <https://www.aboutads.info/choices>. Please note that if you use a different computer, change your web browser, or delete your cookies, you may need to renew your opt-out choices. Your browser or device may include “Do Not Track” functionality.  Our information collection and disclosure practices and the choices we provide will continue as described in this notice, whether or not a Do Not Track signal is received.

### About Law Enforcement and Legal Requests

**Information We Must Disclose**  
We regularly receive legal requests for customer information from government and law enforcement personnel. We also receive discovery requests in civil cases. We cooperate by providing the information required by law. Cox does not volunteer customer information or give access to customer communications to law enforcement or others, except in the "Special Exceptions" detailed above or if we have a good faith belief that an emergency involving a danger of death or serious physical injury requires disclosure. Many criminal subpoenas require that we not disclose or notify you of the request. Due to this fact and the volume of requests we receive, we do not assume any duty to notify you of receipt of any legal requests.

**Internet Information**

We sometimes receive subpoenas for your identity in connection with use of your Internet service for apparent copyright infringement or other civil matters. Files shared over "peer-to-peer" services often include your IP address, and you can be identified in this way if we receive a lawful subpoena. Law enforcement can also obtain details about your Internet use and the content of communications through a warrant or similar authority.

**Telephone Information**

Law enforcement must obtain a warrant or other similar authority to use a telephone wiretap or a device to capture dialing information. Law enforcement can also subpoena account and call record information.

**Cable Television Programming Selections**

Your video programming selections may generally be obtained only under court order and after notice is sent to you and you are given the opportunity to object in court.

About Child Pornography

We work closely with the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children and other groups to eliminate child pornography on the Internet. The law requires us to report any evidence we learn of concerning apparent child pornography.

### Security of Information

We maintain a security program that continues to work on new ways to protect Personally Identifiable Information. For our most sensitive databases, we use encryption within controlled and secured environments that have restricted access. Although we work to ensure the integrity and security of our network and computer systems, no one can guarantee that security measures will prevent unauthorized access or use. We generally retain personal customer information of service applicants, current and former customers for business, tax, or legal purposes, until no longer needed.

### What You Should Know About Children's Privacy

Children should always get permission from a parent or guardian before sending their information over the Internet. Our websites are not directed at, or intended for use by, children under the age of 13. If you believe your child may have provided us with their personal information, you can contact us at the address on your bill and we will delete their personal information. We treat information concerning services provided for family use as that of our adult customer, even if used by a child. We encourage adults to assure responsible use by minors. You can find more information about protecting children's privacy by clicking on " _[Take Charge](https://www.cox.com/aboutus/take-charge.html)_ " on Cox.com or visiting [https://www.ftc.gov](https://www.ftc.gov/).

### Note to California Customers Regarding Your Privacy Rights

California law requires that we provide to certain customers, upon request, certain information regarding the sharing of Personally Identifiable Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We may share Personally Identifiable Information with some affiliates for those affiliates’ direct marketing purposes. If you make a request by sending an email to  _[privacy@cox.com](mailto:privacy@cox.com)_ , we will provide you with a list of personal information that we may have shared with some or all of these affiliates.

### Customer Information Access and Enforcement Rights

You may check the accuracy of your Personally Identifiable Information in your account by contacting a Customer Care representative. You may also examine your Personally Identifiable Information and advise us of any errors you believe we should correct, upon prior request and at your own cost, during business hours at the Cox office listed on your bill. You can enforce your legal privacy rights concerning our collection, use and sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information. Among your remedies is the right to bring a civil action and seek damages, reasonable attorneys’ fees and other litigation costs under 47 U.S.C. Section 551.

### Other Terms and Changes in Policy

Other terms and conditions affect our service offerings, including the online privacy policies for our websites, service contracts, our Acceptable Use Policy for High Speed Internet service, tariffs and the terms of use for our websites and apps. We intend this statement to be part of these documents. Changes in our service offerings or the law may cause us to make changes to this and other policies from time to time. We will post any changes at Cox.com, along with the effective date of the changes.

### Our Network Practices

For more information about our network management practices, please read our Internet Services Disclosures at <https://www.cox.com/aboutus/policies/internet-service-disclosures.html>.

### Customer Proprietary Network Information

If you subscribe to Cox telephone service or any other Cox service classified as a “telecommunications service,” federal law creates certain additional privacy protections and use restrictions with respect to a category of information known as “customer proprietary network information” or “CPNI.” CPNI refers to the quantity, technical configuration, type, destination, location, and amount of your use of a telecommunications service that is made available to us solely by virtue of our relationship with you, as a customer. CPNI also includes information in your bills pertaining to your telephone service. CPNI does not include subscriber list information, such as your name, address and telephone number or other information that has been published in any directory format, or information that does not identify you personally. Examples of CPNI include information about your phone service found on your monthly telephone bill, the technical characteristics of your service, the class of service to which you subscribe, your current telephone charges, your long distance and local service billing records, directory assistance charges, usage data, and calling records.

We have a duty, under federal law, to protect the confidentiality of CPNI. Cox does not sell your CPNI, and your CPNI will not be disclosed to third parties outside of Cox and our affiliates, agents, joint venture partners, vendors, and independent contractors, except as required by law or detailed here.

We may use your telephone CPNI to offer our communications-related products or services that may enhance products or services to which you already subscribe. Unless you tell us otherwise within thirty days of your first receipt of this CPNI notice, we may also use your telephone CPNI to offer you communications-related products or services that are outside of the same category of service to which you already subscribe. You can restrict or withdraw the right for us to use your CPNI for these marketing purposes at any time at <https://www.cox.com/privacyrequest>. When you contact us, we may ask for your consent to use your CPNI in marketing our services to you at that time. This consent applies only for the duration of the call or Internet session. We will not use your CPNI for any other marketing purposes without your permission. Restricting our use of your CPNI will not affect your service. If you previously contacted us to approve or deny our use of your CPNI, we will continue to honor your request and you do not need to contact us again.

### Annual Do-Not-Call Registry Notice

To help reduce unwanted telemarketing calls, the FCC offers telephone subscribers the opportunity to register their residential telephone numbers, including wireless numbers, on its national Do Not Call registry. You may register for the list without charge by calling the FTC toll-free at 1-888-382-1222 or TYY 1-866-290-4236 from the telephone number you are registering, or by going online at www.donotcall.gov. The FCC/FTC rules contain an "established business relationship" exception that permits a company that has such a relationship with you, like Cox, to call even if your number is registered.
